Moments ago, Israel launched Operation
Rising Lion.
A few hours earlier, at the Nevatim
military base in southern Israel, nearly
200 aircraft had taken off.
The scale of the raid was unprecedented.
There were radar planes for the detection
and protection of the raid, and of course,
refueling planes,
because we have a distance of more than
1,500 km So, yeah.
Israel and Iran.
So it's really a very massive raid as we
hadn't seen in the 21st century.
This is one of the most impressive
military operations in modern times.
With formidable efficiency, the IDF
neutralised Iran's air defence systems.
They destroyed Russian S-400s, which are
part of the best anti-aircraft batteries,
which allowed them to conquer Totally
Iranian sky.
Caught off guard, Iran sent its kamikaze
drones into the sky.
But they were immediately destroyed by
Israeli combat helicopters.
Cornered, the leaders of the Revolutionary
Guard Air Force then made a serious
mistake.
They decided to meet to organise a
counter-attack.
The trap set by the IDF was closing in on
them.
They sent encrypted false...
messages to these commanders of the
Iranian IRGC and they brought them
together to
the same bunker.
There were agents also near the locations
in order to ensure that indeed they are
there
and then the Israeli Air Force bombed the
place.
They are aiming at what we call the C2,
that is to say the command system, the
fact.
To target the command at once,
it allows you to create a surprise effect
and it also causes fear.
In retaliation, the Iranian regime fired
more than 500 ballistic missiles at
Israel.
Around 50 of them reached the heart of Tel
Aviv.
Israel retaliated in turn.
It attacked all the symbols of the Islamic
Republic, including the state television
station, Irib News.
Leading figures from the regime were
simply taken out in their Tehran homes.
You could see large towers, and at the top
of them were ultra-luxurious apartments,
so held by the regime's great ponts.
During the 12 days of war, Around 30
high-ranking officials were assassinated.